Guide to the Franklin M. Fisher Papers, 1958-2012 RL.11059
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Franklin M. Fisher papers
1960s-2012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Fisher, Franklin M., 1934-2019
RL.11059
60 Linear Feet
Franklin Marvin Fisher (1934-2019) was an American economist and professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology since 1960 until he became professor emeritus in 2004. The collection includes materials documenting Fisher's professional life as an economist and professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. It contains Fisher's professional correspondence, including letters of recommendation and reader reports; a portion of this series is restricted during Fisher's lifetime. The collection also contains writings by Fisher, including including drafts and typescripts of articles and writings on corporate monopolies, natural resources and commodities, aggregate production, equilibrium, and econometrics. There is also a significant body of work from Fisher's collaboration with Karl Shell on their book, Economic Analysis of Price Production Indexes. Another large portion of the collection documents Fisher's consulting work, especially his role as an expert witness on a variety of monopoly and antitrust cases, including US vs. IBM, Eastman Kodak vs. Polaroid, and US vs. Microsoft. Also represented in the papers is Fisher's role in the Harvard Middle East Water Project, the Peace Now Project, and other projects seeking to bring peace through water allocation. Finally, the papers include details about Fisher's various professional engagements and membership in various associations, as well as his teaching files, lecture notes, and assorted materials related to his appointment at MIT.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into series: Correspondence; Consulting Work, Projects, and Service; Engagements; Lectures and Teaching; and Writings.
Biographical / Historical
Franklin Marvin Fisher (1934-2019) was an economist and professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology. He specialized in industrial organization, microeconomics, and econometrics, and served as an expert witness in numerous antitrust legal cases. He was also involved in projects involving conflict resolution and water management.
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted. Fisher's referee reports and letters of recommendation are closed to research and require written permission from the donor for access. The rest of the collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Franklin M. Fisher Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from Franklin M. Fisher in 2005 and 2012. Acc. 2019-0170 was received as a gift from Ellen Fisher in 2019.
Collection Overview
The Franklin M. Fisher Papers document the research, teaching, writings, and professional activities of noted MIT economist Franklin Fisher. The collection reflects Fisher's wide-ranging interests and expertise, including his collaboration on water management and conflict resolution issues in the Middle East; his work as a legal expert on anti-trust lawsuits for assorted corporations and the U.S. Dept. of Justice; his service as a professor and mentor to numerous economics students, largely between the 1970s and 1990s; and his correspondence with leading economists such as Robert Clower, Frank Hahn, Peter Diamond, and Lawrence Klein. His materials have been arranged into series: Writings, Lectures and Teaching, Engagements, Consulting Work, and Correspondence.
Natural resources; Monopolies -- Economic aspects; Economists -- United States -- Correspondence; Water -- Middle East; Shell, Karl; Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Dept. of Economics
- Correspondence, 1958-2007; undated; 1
  Conditions Governing Access
  The Referee Reports and Recommendations are closed to use. Written permission is required from the donor to access these materials.
  Scope and Contents
  Fisher's Correspondence Series consists largely of professional and academic correspondence relating to his research and consulting work. The General Correspondence subseries documents his exchanges with assorted economists, publishers, law firms, and professional groups. Also included in this subseries is Fisher's correspondence with the Econometric Society. Also held in the Correspondence Series is Fisher's Referee Reports and his Recommendations, which largely relate to his role as a professor and mentor to students at MIT. Be advised that access to these subseries is restricted and requires written permission from Fisher.
  - General correspondence, 1958-2007; 1
    - General: A, 1962-2000 (Box C1)
    - Abraham, Haim, 1984-1988 (Box C1)
    - Alamaro, Moshe, 1992-2001 (Box C1)
    - Alberts, William W., 1988-1990 (Box C1)
    - Ando, Amy, 1995-1996 (Box C1)
    - Arellano, Soledad, 2002 (Box C1)
    - Awerbuch, Shimon, 1985-1991 (Box C1)
    - General: B, 1960-1996; 2 folders (Box C1)
    - Beck, Roger L., 1985-1986 (Box C1)
    - Berndt, Ernst, 1989 (Box C1)
    - Bernheim, Douglas B., 1988-1993 (Box C1)
    - Blackorby, Charles, 1984-1988 (Box C1)
    - Bittlingmayer, George, 1994 (Box C1)
    - Brenner, Reuven, 1986-1990 (Box C1)
    - General: C, 1959-1995 (Box C1)
    - Cahn, Edgar, 1984-1987 (Box C1)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1980-2007 (Box C1)
    - Carlton, Dennis, 1985-2003 (Box C1)
    - Cartelier, Jean, 1988-1990 (Box C1)
    - Charles River Associates, 1979-2000s; 2 folders (Box C2)
    - Chen, C.C., 1988-1995 (Box C2)
    - Chen, Ping, 1992 (Box C2)
    - Clower, Robert W., 1983-1986 (Box C2)
      re: American Economic Review
    - Cravath, Swain, and Moore, 1979-1981 (Box C2)
    - Crawford, Vincent, 1979-1981 (Box C2)
    - General: D, 1963-2003 (Box C2)
    - Dana, James, 1987-1993 (Box C2)
    - Diamond, Peter, 1964-1990 (Box C2)
    - Dhrymes, Phoebus J., 1964-1987 (Box C2)
    - General: E, 1984-1990 (Box C2)
    - The Econometric Society, 1961-1988; 5 folders (Box C2)
    - Economics Letters (publication), 1996-2002 (Box C2)
      correspondence with Eric Maskin
    - Elgar, Edward, 1987-1990 (Box C2)
    - General: F, 1960-1994 (Box C2)
    - Feenstra, Robert, 1991-1993 (Box C3)
    - Felipe, Jesus, 1996 (Box C3)
    - Ferral, Victor E. Jr, 1987-1995 (Box C3)
    - General: G, 1959-1996 (Box C3)
    - The Green Environment Fund, 2001 (Box C3)
    - Greenstein, Shane, 1999 (Box C3)
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1980-1985 (Box C3)
    - General: H, 1962-2006 (Box C3)
    - Hahn, Frank, 1980-1990 (Box C3)
    - Hallogen, Robert, 1997 (Box C3)
    - Hauland, Georges, 1991 (Box C3)
      re: Presses Universitaires de France
    - Hausman, Leonard, 1990-1994 (Box C3)
    - Heertje, A., 1993-1996 (Box C3)
    - Holmes, James M., 1988-1990 (Box C3)
    - Holt, Charles C., 1962-1986 (Box C3)
    - General: I, 1985-1993 (Box C3)
    - General: J, 1983-1997 (Box C3)
    - J. B. Clark Medal, 1974 (Box C3)
      re: Fisher's award
    - Journals (various), 1961-1990 (Box C3)
    - General: K, 1959-1996 (Box C3)
    - Kaysen, Carl, 1959-1991 (Box C3)
    - Klein, Lawrence, 1962 (Box C3)
    - General: L, 1959-2003; 2 folders (Box C3)
    - Levin, Dan, 1984-1990 (Box C3)
    - General: M, 1960-2002; 2 folders (Box C4)
    - Mallela, Parthasaradhi, 1988-1998 (Box C4)
    - Manning, Richard, 1986-1989 (Box C4)
    - Minter Simpson (law firm), 1985 (Box C4)
    - The MIT Press, 1981-1985 (Box C4)
    - Myers, Andy, 1988-1990 (Box C4)
    - Mynbaev, Kairat, 1994-1995 (Box C4)
    - General: N, 1962-1997 (Box C4)
    - Neuberg, Leland G., 1989-1997 (Box C4)
    - Newmark, Craig M., 1989-1991 (Box C4)
    - General: O, 1989-1994 (Box C4)
    - General: P, 1960-2000; 2 folders (Box C4)
    - Patinkin School of Economics, Hebrew University, 1992-1997 (Box C4)
    - Palestine-Israel Journal, 1994 (Box C4)
    - Pearl, Judea, 1994-1997 (Box C4)
    - Praeger Editors, 1982-1984 (Box C4)
    - Publisher's correspondence, general, 1980s (Box C4)
      Includes royalty statements.
    - General: Q, 1987 (Box C4)
    - General: R, 1961-1994; 2 folders (Box C4)
    - Requests for papers, 1970s-1980s (Box C5)
      Unsorted
    - Robinson, Cordula, 2003 (Box C5)
    - Rubenfield, Daniel, 1996-1997 (Box C5)
    - General: S, 1959-2002; 5 folders (Box C5)
    - Sadka, Efraim, 1983-1985 (Box C5)
    - Selective Service System, 1958 (Box C5)
      Deferment demand
    - Solow, Robert, 2003 (Box C5)
    - Stahl, Dale II, 1984-1990; 2 folders (Box C5)
    - Strotz, Robert, 1959-1961 (Box C5)
    - General: T, 1959-1995; 2 folders (Box C5)
    - Tsai, Addison D., 1998 (Box C5)
    - bin Talal, HRH Prince El Hassan (Jordan) re: water in Jordan, 2005-2007 (Box A1)
    - General: U, 1987-2003 (Box C5)
    - General: V, 1988-2002 (Box C5)
    - General: W, 1962-1998; 3 folders (Box C5-C6)
    - Xi, Wusan, 1994-1995 (Box C6)
    - General: Y, 1979-1991 (Box C6)
    - General: Z, 1984-1999 (Box C6)
    - Unknown author, 1960-1982; undated (Box C6)
  - Referee reports, 1964-2002; 2
    - American Economic Review, 1985-1990; 2 folders (Box C6)
    - Congress of the United States Office of Technology Assessment, 1991 (Box C6)
    - Econometrica, 1985-1987 (Box C6)
    - Economic Inquiry, 1991-1992 (Box C6)
    - The Economic Journal, 1994-1996 (Box C6)
    - Federal Judicial Center, 1993 (Box C6)
    - Journal of Economic Education, 1997-2000 (Box C6)
    - Journal of Economic Theory, 1985 (Box C6)
    - Journal of Industry, Competition, and Trade, 2002 (Box C6)
    - Journal of Law, Economics, and Organization, 1992-1995 (Box C6)
    - Quarterly Journal of Economics, 1984-1994 (Box C6)
    - Review of Economic Studies, 1984-1988 (Box C6)
    - Review of Economics and Statistics, 1989 (Box C6)
    - Loose papers, undated (Box C6)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1964-2002; 2 folders (Box C6)
  - Recommendations, 1970s-2000s; 3
    - Miscellaneous recommendations, A-Z, 1970s-2000s; 4 folders (Box C7)
    - Ai, Chunrong, 1985-1990 (Box C7)
    - Amir, Ilan, 1997-1998 (Box C7)
    - Arcand, Jean-Louise, 1990-1991 (Box C7)
    - Agarwell, Roy Shree, 1999 (Box C7)
    - Anderson, Richard, 1979-1984; 2 folders (Box C7)
    - Bernheim, Douglas B., 1984-1985 (Box C7)
    - Carroll, Kathleen, 1992-1993; 2 folders (Box C7)
    - Chang, Howard, 1991 (Box C7)
    - Chevalier, Judy, 1992-1993 (Box C7)
    - Chipty, Tasmeem, 1992 (Box C7)
    - Dana, James (Jim), 1987-1991 (Box C7)
    - Demsetz, Rebecca, 1990-1991 (Box C7)
    - Ellison, Glenn, 2000 (Box C7)
    - Ettner, Susan, 1990 (Box C7)
    - Genesove, David, 1995 (Box C7)
    - Ichino, Andrea, 1988-1994 (Box C8)
    - Kehoe, Timothy, 1984 (Box C8)
    - Kende, Michael, 1994-1997 (Box C8)
    - Levin, Daniel, 1981-1982 (Box C8)
    - Liebowitz, Stan, 1984-1991 (Box C8)
    - Machina, Mark, 1984-1994 (Box C8)
    - Mayer, Chris, 1991 (Box C8)
    - Ming, Song, 1985 (Box C8)
    - Mullin, Wallace, 1991 (Box C8)
    - Postrel, Steven, 1986 (Box C8)
    - Prager, Robin, 1984-1988 (Box C8)
    - Raff, Daniel, 1982-1985 (Box C8)
    - Rose, Nancy, 1984-1994 (Box C8)
    - Saldanha, Fernando, 1981-1988 (Box C8)
    - Saloner, Garth, 1987-1989 (Box C8)
    - Scheffman, David, 1980-1988 (Box C8)
    - Schinkel, Maartin-Pieter, 1994-1997; 2 folders (Box C8)
    - Shleifer, Andrei, 1982-1985 (Box C8)
    - Schworm, William, 1986-1993 (Box C8)
    - Scott-Morton, Fiona, 1993 (Box C8)
    - Shepard, Andrea, 1989-1991 (Box C8)
    - Smith, John, 1992 (Box C8)
    - Spady, Richard, 1977-1980 (Box C8)
    - Spector, David, 1998-2008 (Box C8)
    - Stahl, Dale, 1990-1996 (Box C8)
    - Wen, Mei, 1991-1992 (Box C8)
- Lectures and Teaching, 1961-2009; 2.0 Linear Feet 1 paige box, 1 document case
  The Lectures and Teaching Series contains assorted materials from Fisher's economics classes at MIT, including exams, problem sets, and notes from Economic Principles, Microeconomic Theory, and others. The series also contains some lecture notes from Fisher's 1984 trip to China and other miscellaneous events. Additional materials related to public lectures can be found in the Writings and Engagements series.
  - Disequilibrium Foundations of Equilibrium Foundations (14.1.41), 1990s; 3 folders (Box L1)
    Course materials, reading lists, reading materials
  - Economic Principles (14.01) exams, 1980s-1990s; 3 folders (Box L1)
  - Economic Principles (14.01) outline, 1990s-1998 (Box L1)
  - Economic Principles (14.01) problem sets, 1980s-1990s; 6 folders (Box L1)
  - Intermediate Applied Economics (14.03), 1990s (Box L1)
  - Microeconomic Theory I (14.121), 1990s-2000s; 2 folders (Box L1)
    Outlines, notes, exams, problem sets
  - Microeconomic Theory II (14.122), 1980s-1990s; 3 folders (Box L2)
    Reading lists, exams, problem sets, and other miscellaneous material
  - Various notes and miscellaneous materials, 1961-1992; undated; 2 folders (Box L2)
  - Lectures on Microeconomics, delivered in China, 1984 (Box L2)
  - Running out of Water, MIT Women's League Lecture, 2009 (Box L2)
- Writings, 1958-2010; 1; 10.5 Linear Feet
  Fisher's Writings Series has been divided into subseries: Articles and Essays; Miscellaneous Notes and Reviews; Books (which includes his Collected Works); and Work with Karl Shell. The Articles and Essays subseries documents Fisher's wide-ranging professional interests, including writings on corporate monopolies, natural resources and commodities, aggregate production, equilibrium, and econometrics. Some of these articles overlap with the Karl Shell subseries. The majority of the Karl Shell subseries relates to Fisher and Shell's collaboration on their book, Economic Analysis of Price Production Indexes, including correspondence, drafts, and research. Materials from other books by Fisher are represented in the Books subseries, but researchers should be advised that not every book written by Fisher is represented in the collection, and some titles have only book reviews or supplemental materials. The Books subseries also includes drafts and preparatory material from the publication of Fisher's Collected Works. Finally, Fisher's Miscellaneous Notes subseries includes some unidentified notes, as well as assorted book reviews and other writings by Fisher commenting on other economics research.
  - Articles and Essays, 1958-2003; 1
    - Accounting Data and the Economic Performance of Firms, 1988 (Box W1)
    - Acerca del uso Independiente de Dos a Mas de Variables de la Politica Economica, 1963 (Box W1)
      In Revista de Economia Latinoamericana, Vol. 10
    - Adjustment Process and Stability, 1986 (Box W1)
      In the New Palgrave, MacMillan edition.
    - Aggregate Price Indices, New Goods and Generics, 1994; 2 folders (Box W1)
    - Aggregate Production Functions and the Explanation of Wages: A Simulation Experiment, 1971 Nov. (Box W1)
    - Aggregate Production Functions: Some CES Experiments, 1974-1977 (Box W1)
      Includes working paper.
    - Aggregate Production Functions Revisited: The Mobility of Capital and the Rigidity of Thought, 1982 (Box W1)
    - Aggregation in Production Functions: What Applied Economists Should Know, 2003 (Box W1)
    - Aggregation over Goods and the Factor-Intensity Reversal Qualification to the Heckscher-Ohlin Theorem, 1979 May (Box W1)
    - Alcoa Revisited: Comment, 1974 (Box W1)
    - An Alternate Proof and Extension of Solow's Theorem on Non-Negative Square Matrices, 1962 (Box W1)
    - An Analysis of Boston Voting Patterns 1963-1967, 1968 (Box W1)
    - Analyzing Agricultural Demand for Water with an Optimizing Model, 1999 (Box W1)
    - Antitrust and Innovative Industries, undated (Box W1)
    - Approximate Aggregation and the Leontief Conditions, 1969 July (Box W1)
    - Approximate Specification and the Choice of a K-Class Estimator, 1967 (Box W1)
    - Architectural Bias in CRS: The Loss and Consumer Welfare, 1992 June (Box W1)
    - The Audience-Revenue Relationship for Local Television Stations, 1980 (Box W1)
    - Aspects of Cost-Benefit Analysis in Defense Manpower Planning, undated (Box W1)
    - BOC Manufature of Telecommunicationis Equipment: An Assessment of Benefits and Competitive Risks, 1995 (Box W1)
    - Causation and Specification in Economic Theory and Econometrics, 1969 (Box W1)
    - Choice of Units, Column Sums, and Stability in Linear Dynamic Systems with Nonnegative Square Matrices, 1965 (Box W1)
    - The Choice of Instrumental Variables in the Estimation of Economy-Wide Econometric Models: Some Further Thoughts, 1970 (Box W1)
    - The Commodity Pattern of Trade and the Heckscher-Ohlin Theorem in the Presence of Aggregate and Commodity-Specific Factor-Intensity Reversals, 1983 (Box W1)
    - Community Antenna Television Systems and Local Television Station Audiences, 1966 (Box W1)
    - Community Antenna Television Systems and the Regulation of Television Broadcasting, 1966 (Box W1)
    - Continuously Dated Commodities, Individual Price Adjustment, and Non-Tatonnement with Production and Consumption, 1975 (Box W1)
    - A Correspondence Principle for Simultaneous Equation Models, 1970 Jan. (Box W1)
    - The Cost and Effectiveness of Reenlistment Incentives in the Navy, 1967 (Box W1)
    - The Costs of Automobile Model Changes since 1949, 1962 Oct. (Box W1)
    - Cournet Oligopoly and Government Regulation, undated (Box W1)
    - The Covariance Matrix of the Limited Information Estimator and the Identification Test: Comment, 1972 (Box W1)
    - Decomposability, Near Decomposability, and Balanced Price under CRS, 1963 (Box W1)
    - Diagnosing Monopoly, 1978-1980 (Box W1)
      Includes lecture and reply
    - Discussion, 1971 (Box W1)
      In the Tax Incentives and Capital Spending volume
    - Due Diligence and the Demand for Electricity: A Cautionary Tale, 1991-1992 (Box W1)
    - Dynamic Structure and Estimations in Economy-Wide Econometric Model, 1965 (Box W1)
    - The Early Chapters of Genesis: An Economist's View, 1988 (Box W1)
    - An Economic Approach to Water Allocation, approximately 1998 (Box A1)
    - An Econometric Model of the World Copper Industry, 1972 (Box W1)
    - An Econometric Simulation Model of Intra-Metropolitan Housing Location: Housing, Business, Transportation, and Local Government, 1972 (Box W1)
    - Econometricians and Adversary Proceedings, 1984-1986 (Box W1)
    - Economics of Sports Leagues: The Chicago Bulls Case, 1999 (Box W1)
    - The Economics of Sports Leagues and the Relocation of Teams: The Case of the St. Louis Rams, 2000 (Box W1)
    - The Economics of Water Dispute Resolution, Project Evaluation and Management: An Application to the Middle East, 1995 (Box W1)
    - The Educational Opportunity Bank: An Economic Analysis of a Contingent Repayment Loan Program for Higher Education, 1968 (Box W1)
    - The Effect of the Removal of the Firemen on Railroad Accidents, 1962-1967, 1971 (Box W1)
    - The Effects of Simple Specification Error on the Coefficients of Unaffected Variables, 1977 (Box W1)
    - Embodied Technical Change and the Existence of an Aggregate Capital Stock, 1965 (Box W1)
    - Embodied Technology and the Aggregation of Fixed and Movable Capital Goods, 1968 (Box W1)
    - Embodied Technology and the Existence of Labor and Output Aggregators, 1968 (Box W2)
    - Employment Discrimination and Statistical Science: Comment, 1987 (Box W2)
    - The Existence of the Aggregate Production Functions, 1969-1971 (Box W2)
      Includes reply
    - The Formation of Economic Magnitudes: Disequalibrium and Stability, 1986-1988 (Box W2)
    - Games Economists Play: A Noncooperative View, 1987 (Box W2)
    - Generalization of the Rank and Order Conditions for Identifiability, 1959 (Box W2)
    - Gross Substitutes and the Utility Function, 1971-1972 (Box W2)
    - The Hahn Process with Firms but No Production, 1974 (Box W2)
    - Herman O. A. Wold and the Nobel Prize, 1984 (Box W2)
      Includes addendum
    - Horizontal Mergers: Triage and Treatment, 1987; 2 folders (Box W2)
      Includes multiple drafts, working paper, proofs, and JEP Horizontol Merger Reform Symposium (Nov. 1986)
    - Household Equivalence Scales and Interpersonal Comparisons, 1986-1987 (Box W2)
      Includes multiple versions, research material
    - Household Equivalence Scales: Reply, 1989 (Box W2)
      Includes multiple versions
    - How Income Ought to be Distributed: Paradox Enow, 1962 (Box W2)
      In JPE, Vol. 70, No. 1, Feb. 1962
    - How Income Ought to be Distributed: Paradox Lost, 1961 (Box W2)
      In JPE, Vol. 69, No. 2, Apr 1961
    - The IBM and Microsoft Cases: What's the Difference, 2000 (Box W2)
    - IBM and the U.S. EDP Industry, 1982; undated (Box W2)
      Includes Correspondence, Corrections
    - Identifiability Criteria in Nonlinear Systems/Identifiability Criteria in Nonlinear Systems: A Further Note, 1961; 1965 (Box W2)
    - Income Distribution, Value Judgements, and Welfare, 1956 (Box W2)
      Includes paper and comments
    - Influenza degli incentivi economici sulla perforazione dei pozzi esplorativi e sulla scoperta di nuovi giacimenti negli stati uniti, 1964 (Box W2)
      In La Scuola in Azione
    - Innovation and Monopoly Leveraging, undated (Box W2)
    - Innovative Industries and Antitrust: Comments on The Microsoft Antitrust Case, 2001 (Box W2)
    - An Inter-Seasonal Agricultural Water Allocation System (SAWAS), 2000 (Box W2)
    - It takes t. to Tango: Trading Coalitions with Fixed Prices, 1988-1989 (Box W2)
      Includes multiple versions, referee's report
    - Janis Joplin's Yearbook and the Theory of Damages, 1989-1990 (Box W2)
    - Liquid Assets: The Economics of Water in the Middle East. A Preliminary Report of the Harvard Middle East Water Project, 1995 (?) (Box W2)
    - Market Definition: A User's Guide, 2002 (Box W2)
    - The Mathematical Analysis of Supreme Court Decisions: The Use and Abuse of Quantitative Methods, 1958 (Box W2)
      In the American Political Science Review, June 1958
    - Matsushita: Myth V. Analysis in the Economics of Predation, 1989 (Box W2)
      Includes multiple versions, drafts, notes
    - Memorial Talk for Yitzhak Rabin - MIT - November 6, 1995 (Box W2)
    - Memoirs of the Water Project, 1993-1995 (Box A1)
    - A Metric for Assessing the "Goodness" of Income Distributions and the Effect of Price Changes, 2002 (Box W2)
    - Misconceptions, Misdirections, and Mistakes, 2000 (Box W2)
      Includes draft, research materials
    - Misunderstanding Monopoly: IBM and Antitrust in Retrospect, 1993 (Box W2)
    - Multiple Regression in Legal Proceedings, 1979; 1981 (Box W2)
      Includes working paper, research material
    - My Career in Economics: A Hindcast, 1995 (?) (Box W2)
    - Near-Decomposability Partition and Aggregation, and Relevance of Stability Discussions, 1963 (Box W2)
      In International Economics Review, Vol. 4, No. 1, Jan 1963
    - Near-Identifiability and the Variance of the Disturbance Terms, 1965 (Box W3)
      In Econometrica, Vol. 33, No. 2, Apr. 1965
    - Negro-White Savings Differentials and the Modigliani-Brumberg Hypothesis, 1958 (Box W3)
      In RES, Vol. 40, No. 1, Feb. 1958
    - New Developments on the Oligopoly Front: Cournot and the Bain-Sylos Analysis, 1959 (Box W3)
      In JPE, Vol. 67, No. 4, Aug. 1959
    - A Non-Tatonnement Model with Production and Consumption, 1976 (Box W3)
      In Econometrica, Vol. 44, No. 5, Sept. 1976
    - Normal Goods and the Expenditure Function, 1989 (Box W3)
      Including multiple versions, referee reports
    - A Note on Estimation from a Cauchy Sample, 1964 (Box W3)
    - On Choosing (and Using) an Expert Economist, undated (Box W3)
    - On Donor Sovereignty and United Charities, 1977 (Box W3)
    - On Perfect Aggregation in the National Output Deflator and Generalized Rybczynski Theorems, 1982 (Box W3)
    - On Predation and Victimless Crime, 1986 (Box W3)
      Includes paper, notes, comment
    - On Price Adjustment without an Auctioneer, 1972 (Box W3)